Some say you can tell a lot about a person by the way they decorate their home.
有人说，从一个人装饰家的方式就能看出他的很多特质。
We often find pleasure in the things we stick in our houses, be it trinket we bought on holiday, film memorabilium or painting to liven up walls.
我们总乐于在家中摆放一些物件，比如度假时买的小饰品、电影纪念品，或是能让墙面焕发生机的画作。
And when we head to others’ houses, we often see things we appreciate, but wouldn’t have in our own homes, because maybe they’re not quite to our taste.
当我们去别人家做客时，也常会看到一些自己欣赏、却不会放在自家的东西，可能只是因为这些东西不太合自己的口味。
The point is, the way we decorate our homes is very personal.
关键是，家装的方式极具个人色彩。
And while many of us have plenty of stuff, there are always people who go that little bit further.
虽然我们很多人家里的东西已经不少，但总有人会想要更多。
So, when it comes to minimalism and maximalism, which one appeals to you more?
那么，说到极简主义和极繁主义这两种风格，你更偏爱哪一种呢？
Minimalism was an art movement that started in the 1950s. Its basic principles are derived from a concept of ‘less is more’ – reducing things back to their most basic.
极简主义是20世纪50年代兴起的一场艺术运动，其基本原则源于“少即是多”的理念——将事物还原至最本质的状态。
Some people took that art style and used it as a way of living.
一些人将这种艺术风格运用到了生活方式中。
Ideas of vast open space with an organised and functional structure may spring to mind.
人们想到这种风格，往往会浮现出开阔敞亮、布局规整且实用性强的空间画面。
They are usually decorated in simple pastel colour, with many minimalists opting for duotone, often just black and white.
这类家居通常采用简约的柔和色调，许多极简主义者还会选择双色搭配，通常就是黑与白。
For some, especially maximalists, it may seem sparse and a bit bland to live without many things – even boring or depressing.
对有些人来说，尤其是极繁主义者，生活中少了很多物件，会显得空旷单调，甚至有些乏味沉闷。
However, living in this way is seen by many as more practical.
但在很多人看来，这种生活方式其实更为实用。
Maximalism is the opposite of minimalism and started in the 1970s. It embraces the core ideals that ‘more is more’.
极繁主义诞生于20世纪70年代，是极简主义的对立面，它信奉“多即是多”的核心理念。
While minimalism centres around the principle of decluttering, it’s easy to imagine that a maximalist home is overflowing with items – but that’s not the base idea.
极简主义的核心是清理冗余物品，由此很容易让人联想到极繁主义的家会堆满各种物件——但这并非其本意。
It’s more about filling the space – making the most of the area.
极繁主义更强调充实空间，充分利用每一处区域。
Structured excess and bold colour combined with mixed pattern is what you will see in a home like this.
这种风格的家居，呈现出的是规整的繁复感、大胆的色彩运用以及多样的图案混搭。
For a minimalist, used to more simplistic designs, it could be overwhelming.
对于习惯了简约设计的极简主义者而言，这样的空间可能会让人觉得眼花缭乱。
But for those who embrace it, those things give a space personality.
但对钟爱极繁风格的人来说，这些元素恰恰赋予了空间独特的个性。
The way you have your home is up to you!
家的风格终究由你做主！
But, if you opt for maximalism, you may need to prepare for a bit more dusting.
不过，如果你选择了极繁主义，那可得做好多花些时间打扫除尘的准备。